Wait, wait, Sam, you got to click bait
it up. How a $5 billion founder is using
AI to change his life.
>> Well, are you a five What are you guys
worth now?
>> Who knows?
>> You know. You know. You. You.
All right, we should do a little intro.
So, first do you Is it I've been saying
Zapier my whole life.
Is it Zapier or Zapier?
>> Zapier makes you happier is the trick.
>> It [clears throat] rhymes with happier.
Happier. Wow. Dude, how is that not your
slogan? Here's your Here's what your
slogan is on your site. The automation
layer for agentic AI. It doesn't really
flow the same way as Zapier makes you
happier.
>> It doesn't. We could So, there's two
things from the name. We one, we just
couldn't afford the second P when we
started. Like, the domain was available.
But, the other like, we were too clever
for our own good is
it has API in the name, which we always
thought like, "Oh, that's neat." Cuz
it's all
connecting all the these APIs and all
that good stuff.
>> I didn't even notice that. Didn't notice
that.
>> Yeah.
>> Honestly, didn't even notice the P was
missing.
>> [laughter]
>> But, it also if you played Zapier makes
you happier, I would have read it as
Zapier makes you happier.
>> [laughter]
>> Just gone on with your day.
But, we're happier here.
>> Thank you.
>> The short story is you're this guy who's
built this really cool started off as a
very simple idea where you can make
different apps connect with each other.
What does that really mean? Let's say I
have a business and people submit a form
over here on my form thing, but then I
kind of need that form thing I need all
the people who submitted the form I need
that data to go over here in this other
unrelated app. And you guys built those
like universal plugs and you can just
plug in anything to anything else and it
was just incredibly useful. Sam used it,
I used it. We didn't realize or I didn't
realize how monstrous of a business this
had become. I believe you guys are worth
several billions, maybe five billion was
a number that I had seen at some point
in time. And I think you had
bootstrapped a very long way. I don't Is
it purely bootstrapped or you at some
point took some money?
>> I think the word people call it now is
seed strapped. So, we did go through YC
and we raised about a million in change,
but that's all the primary capital we've
ever taken.
>> Yeah, so just incredibly to to raise a
million bucks and then get to 5 billion
in value is just pretty pretty wild. So,
super cool, but we're here not to
necessarily tell the whole story of how
Zapier makes you happier, but to show us
what you're doing with AI.
>> Can you give me a public sales pitch
real quick? I'm requesting a sales pitch
and what I want is I know how
OG V1 of Zapier worked where you connect
one app to another. You're saying, "Hey,
we have this new AI product that you use
with Claude, presumably makes your
Claude or ChatGPT usage more powerful,
whatever." I haven't been using that.
I also, here's the other caveat, I'm
kind of dumb. So, like imagine talking
to somebody with half [laughter] the IQ
of yours.
>> He's like, "Can you give me a pitch to
someone who's sort of dumb and doesn't
listen?"
>> But he's still smart at the same time.
[laughter]
The confidence of a smart man.
>> I have really good news for you, though.
Like I think AI is
this incredible gift to people who are
kind of dumb.
>> [laughter]
>> Because
you can just Agreed. talk to it and say
like, "Hey, I didn't understand that
answer. Explain it to me like I'm five."
And so, you can keep like going down the
dumbness stack, I guess, for like lack
of a better word, until you understand
it and then go, "Okay, now like teach me
back up to where I need to go." So,
okay.
The sales pitch. You want the sales
pitch. In the old world, you know
Zapier, you know, come in, build
integrations, connect apps.
The new world has a lot of the same
things, but it's different. Nowadays,
you're hanging in Claude, you're hanging
in, you know, Codeax or Cursor or you
know, Open Claude or what whatever it is
that you like using, right? And you're
just talking to it going back and forth.
Most people start with that. AI as a
chatbot is valuable, but it's only
generally smart. It knows everything
that the internet knows. It doesn't know
anything about your business.
So, the next stack that you need to go
to is to start connecting your tools.
You start connecting your CRM, your help
desk, your email, your team chat, all
this other stuff, and you feed that
context in to the AI. Now, when you
start asking it questions about My First
Million and all this other stuff, you
get not just generally smart answers.
You get hyper-specific answers around
how your business works, okay? So, if
you install Zapier into this, you can
hook up any of the tools that we have,
right?
So, that's that's the first thing. The
first bit of value and the first thing
that people sort of experience is like,
"Oh, connecting stuff makes sense." But,
look, you can do native connectors and
all that other stuff. So, you know, use
Zapier or use the native connectors, do
whatever you want. The next layer, and
where this gets really powerful, is not
where you're sitting having this like
back-and-forth conversation. It's when
you're actually deploying automations
and agents to actually go operate for
you while you sleep. Like, that's where
you start to get the real magic. And the
reason you want to use Zapier to do that
versus like any of these generic agent
builders
>> What was an example
>> I mean, like, you know, Claude has
routines or ChatGPT has scheduled stuff.
Like, you know, there's a bunch of these
things that can kind of kind of do
agents or pseudo agents these days. But,
the nice thing about Zapier is that if
you use us, we are going to make it so
that whatever you build is optimized to
run more deterministically than
agentically. And I don't think people
caught up on this yet. But, you've
probably experienced it.
>> up the IQ scale.
>> I know. Hang tight. Hang tight. Hang
tight. Agents Agents,
they kind of just guess what to do,
right? And if they're smart enough, they
guess right most of the time. But,
sometimes the agents guess wrong.
And the second thing is agents are using
tokens, right? We probably heard token
maxing, right?
And so they're really expensive.
But if you use Zapier, we're going to
write code for you, and we're going to
write workflow logic for you, which
means that it's going to run like a
machine runs. And so you're going to get
It's not going to burn tokens.
It's going to be reliable and accurate,
and it's only going to use AI exactly
where it needs to to to use AI.
>> Got you.
>> And you've got this um you can host it
on zapier.com, so you don't have to sit
here and like keep your laptop open to
run these agents in the background. And
so you just get this like rock-solid
infrastructure that Zapier has always
been great at, the hookup of everything
that we've always done. But you can
build uh yeah, inside Claude. Which is
like really nice because Claude just
kind of it's the the natural language
style of building is I don't know, it's
just like way better than the no-code
style stuff that we were doing in the
past.
>> Well, you're not the Wolf of Wall
Street, but that was a pretty good sales
pitch. I gave you the sell me this pen
test, and you did a pretty good job
there. So I appreciate that. I feel like
I now actually understand it, so that
that was good.
>> Well, and here's the magic. You can take
If you didn't, and you're just
pretending and being nice, you can take
the transcript of this, and you can plug
it into Claude and say, "Wait said this
weird thing. I think I did it
Tell me what he was really saying."
And that's like the cool part of AI.
>> That is cool.
>> You gave us a list of stuff, so we said,
"Wait,
what are you what are you making?" And
it doesn't always have to be like this
like crazy like game-changing stuff. But
what are you making with AI? And you
gave us a list of like three or four
things. You said you have robot staff.
>> Sam, you got to clickbait it up.
How a $5 billion founder is using AI to
change his life.
>> You Well, are you a five What are you
guys worth now?
>> Who knows?
>> You.
>> [laughter]
>> You I mean, you do.
>> I don't know how the markets behave
right now. They're like up and down all
sorts of ways. Like I think
>> your guess be?
>> I don't think about it, honestly. Like
I'm just like, how do we build stuff
that makes our customers successful?
>> you were a sweet guy. I didn't think you
were a liar, though. Because I know you
think about it.
>> under oath, you know that, right?
>> There's There's the old saying, right?
Like, in the short term, the markets are
a voting machine. In the long term,
they're a weighing machine.
>> I'd rather you just tell me F off than
give me these lies, cuz I know you think
about it. But don't don't piss in my
back and tell me it's rain waiting.
Honestly, don't. Just tell me to tell me
it's none of my business, and I'd accept
it.
>> All right, it's none of your business,
right? Is that Is that helpful?
>> fair.
>> [laughter]
>> Since the last time you guys got value.
When did you Where did the 5 billion
number come from in the first place?
>> That was a secondary number sale that
happened in 2021, maybe?
>> Okay. Are our revenues
slightly up, way up, down, way down
since then? [clears throat]
>> Revenues are up, yeah.
>> Okay. All right, good. So, we're doing
well. All right. The clickbait headline
holds. Okay, continue on. So, how how
you're actually using AI
as a as a high-functioning CEO?
>> Okay. Let me share screen on some of
this stuff.
So, we'll get into the to the fun bits.
One of the cool things is, you know,
because I work with my agent all the
time, I can say, "Hey, I'm, you know,
going on my first million. Like, help me
help me demo this stuff." And so,
this is this is what it came up with.
It's like, "Here's the stuff you should
actually go go demo."
And so, you can see I've got, you know,
four potential things we can show off.
One is the robot staff. This is kind of
like my chief of staff that does like a
whole bunch of different automations and
agents for me. I've got the CEO CEO CRM
that I built that
helps me
stay really close with our enterprise
customers.
Um I've got a like an AI that argues
back. I think this is a really important
thing that
every like leader needs to to build. I
think there's a lot of CEOs out there, a
lot of leaders out there that are
talking to an AI that just agrees with
them all the time.
And so, you need to
um
Like, there's a few ticks and tips and
tricks you can do to like force it to
like scrutinize your thinking rather
than just tell you, "Yeah, you're you're
totally right." all the time.
And then I've got a bunch of skills that
I run for a whole bunch of random tasks
internally. So, yeah, I I would probably
start with the robot staff. I think this
is like cool to to dig into.
The first thing and we'll we'll I'll
show the complete version of this.
Where I think most people start is kind
of the morning brief. You know, it's
super simple.
It's a good
It It's a good way to experience like
your first agent. You know, you hook it
up to your calendar, you hook it up to
your email, you hook it up to your you
know, any meeting
like notes you've got, any
prioritization, like a to-do list that
you have. And then, you know, in this
case it runs at 6:00 a.m. in the morning
and then it sends me
a Slack message.
>> Yeah, I call I call this waking up like
the president. Like the president wakes
up, gets a gets a daily brief. Here's
what Sir, here's what you have on your
your plate today. 9:30 you're talking to
this person, 10:00 a.m. this person's
here, here's what they want to talk
about. That sort of thing. And so,
waking up like every Now everybody gets
to wake up with a presidential briefing.
>> Exactly. And so, you know, these things
run like in my case, I have it send me a
Slack message. You can have it send you
an email. I mean, heck, you could
probably have it fax you something if
you really want to feel like the
president.
>> I have it set up so it prints. But it
doesn't it doesn't do it all the time.
And I also have this woman named Ari
conveniently because I told uh I I
wanted to make it come from
like a a person and the person I named
it after
>> Is that weird for you that Sam named his
agent after you?
>> [laughter]
>> The person they selected looked at
looked like Ari. So, I was like,
"It's Ari." So, I have Ari that sends me
like a pump up speech as well for the
day. So, I love these daily briefs.
>> There you go. Now, so the cool thing,
I'll actually show you. So, I I have the
link out to this one. This is you know,
this is running on Zapier and you can
see what this actually looks like. You
know, it kind of looks like you know,
classic Zapier a little bit. It of every
day at 6:00 a.m. It goes and fetches all
the calendar events.
And then here it's um writing some
specific code and hitting the AI to like
write the Slack in a very particular
way. Now, what is different about this
is we can poke over here.
This is all code. Which in the past like
you couldn't do this with Zapier. Now,
I've not actually looked at any of this
code. Like this is actually the first
time I popped this open and even taken a
look at what this is. So, you don't have
to know what's going on here. Um but
again, it kind of speaks to the value
prop of Zapier is it's turning all of
this stuff into a deterministic workflow
and it's only using AI in the places
that you really need to use AI, which
means this runs way more reliably, way
more consistently,
and way more cost-effectively than than
most agents. So,
>> But can I use this instead? Like the
problem that I have with Claude or
Perplexity or whatever is that my
computer has to be open for a lot of
these routines to run.
>> Exactly.
>> And it's a pain in the ass.
>> Mhm.
>> Would would doing it on Zapier just be
like in lieu of using like open claw or
having a Mac mini?
>> There you go. Exactly the the point. You
can just deploy these as Zapier and we
run them in the cloud for you.
>> That sounds way better than using open
claw or having a Mac mini.
>> It's a way way simpler, right?
You can look up here. It's also agent
managed. So, one of the nice things is
>> All right, hold on just a second. I know
what you're doing. Wade, who started a
company grew to a $5 billion valuation.
He's telling you all these amazing AI
prompts that he uses for his business.
You're probably taking a lot of notes
right now. That's exactly what I was
doing. And so, what we decided to do was
take all of those notes, all of the
scripts that he's talking about, and we
put it into a really easy document. So,
you just copy and paste everything. So,
there's the prompts where he talks about
AI arguing back with him, where he can
stress test different decisions by
having a seven-person AI executive
committee kind of help him figure things
out, and then your own life coach, so
you can have a better day. So, if you
want this exact AI workflow, again, you
can just copy and paste all this stuff.
Just click the link in the description
or scan the QR code. All right, back to
Wade.
>> While it is running deterministically,
if for whatever reason it breaks, like
say an API is down, or you know,
something doesn't work right,
it falls back to having an AI try and
troubleshoot for you. So, it
automatically apply fixes,
you know, when things don't work quite
the right way. And so, there's this like
really nice blend of like traditional
software and like agentic software here
that is just um you know, super well
done by by the team over here.
So, I I definitely would say, "Hey, if
you're if you're struggling with your
open claws, if you're like keeping your
laptop open all the time, you should
definitely install Zapier into like
your, you know, agent or AI of choice
and and give this a try."
>> Okay, what else? So, you get the morning
brief. That's pretty standard, I would
say.
>> talk about So, I think the morning brief
is pretty standard, but the one that I
really like is the the evening brief in
the scribe. So, you know, I've had I
played with a couple versions of it. One
is it runs after every meeting, and then
I have another version that runs at the
end of the day. I actually think this is
way better than the morning brief brief.
And the reason why is you can actually
have the AI help you do stuff.
So, you know, it this loops over all of
my meeting notes from the day. So, I'm
using Granola for all of my meetings.
It loops over all of the to-do's that
are still in my to-do list for the day.
It loops over all of the outstanding
emails that are in my inbox for the day,
and it and then it prompts me and says,
"Hey, how did the day go?"
So, there's two key things that it does
for me. One, when I say what how the day
went, I basically said, "It was a good
day for this reason, or it was a bad day
for this reason." So, now all that stuff
is getting logged, and it's learning how
to tune my day to help me have more good
days than bad days.
>> Oh, that's interesting.
>> thing that it's doing is it's actually
taking action on them stuff on stuff.
So, it says, "Hey, you know, you were
in a meeting with Sam and Shawn
yesterday, and they asked for an intro
to your buddy over at this company. Do
you want me to go ahead and make that
intro for you?" Great, please do that.
All right? So, it's drafting those
follow-up emails. It's drafting all
these other things. And so, this is
where AI starts to get really helpful is
it's not just
giving you a brief and sort of teeing it
up for you to do. It's now saying, "I'll
just do that for you." And this is where
I think you start to really feel the
power of AI is when you can actually put
it to work. So, I love Scribe, the sort
of like post-meeting follow-up or the
end-of-the-day wrap-up because it just I
don't know. I used to spend like 2 hours
at the end of my day just like
you know, just trying to catch up on
every little ticky-tack thing that I
sort of got roped into. And now that
like 2 hours at the end of the day is
down to like 15 minutes.
>> So, you think this is legit saving you 2
hours a day almost?
>> I Yes. Yes. And furthermore, that like,
you know, what's good about my day,
what's bad about my day part, it just
helps me stay like focused on the things
that matter. So, both the AI is helping
me with that, but I also will send like
I remember 90 like about about 90 days
after I started doing this, I said,
"Hey, I had this thought. I was like,
you know so much about like what makes
me have good days and bad days. Can you
like summarize like what is common about
my good days and what is common about my
bad days?" It was like, "Sure." And it
did all that stuff. And then I gave it
to my assistant and I said, "Hey, here's
like Please make my days look like more
good days versus bad days."
>> What What were your good days and what
were your bad days? What did they say?
>> me like the single most important thing
is I'm a morning person. And so, I do my
best work in the morning. I'm most
focused. Um you know, once once after
lunch comes around, you know, I'm just
not going to get anything like serious
done. And so, the most important thing
is I don't want a meeting until 11:00
a.m.
And so, you just give me that morning
time where I can knock out the most
critical things,
and the day's going to go great. Like, I
will win the rest of the day. But, if I
have to like,
you know, if if if
that time starts to get sucked into like
firefighting mode, you can tell I'll
just be grumpy at the end of the day
where I'm just like, like, I'm not I'm
not being successful. And you'll notice
this podcast started at 11:00 a.m.
>> [laughter]
>> Can you show us
how to get the AI to challenge you
instead of
uh
>> Let's do that. So,
coming back, AI that argues back. So,
this is pretty simple, right? I use I
use Cursor as my daily like agent. But,
uh if you're using Claude, if you're
using ChatGPT, if you're using Gemini,
they often have like a system prompt or
a way that you can sort of tune like how
it talks to you.
And so, in Cursor, I have a file as the
agents.md. That's kind of what it uses
everywhere. Claude has a Claude.md
And basically, I have a file that's
like, how to work with me. And, you
know, I
you know, have it be direct and honest.
I need the truth my coworkers are afraid
to tell me. I need you to challenge my
assumptions. I need you to poke holes in
my thinking.
I need you to disag- like, disagree when
you genuinely disagree. And these things
are like goal-seeking entities. And so,
if you tell it like, what I want from
you is this, it's going to say, "Okay,
well, that's what Wade's wants. So, I'm
going to try and give him that goal."
But, if you don't tell him this,
if you don't make this configuration,
it's going to just genuinely try and
like placate you because it thinks
that's what you want. And so, you do
have to tell it you know, you sort of
guide it a little bit.
So, like, here's an example of like, you
know, a live prompt I ran ahead of time
for this. I said, "Hey, I'm thinking we
should kill our entire free tier this
quarter because one of our competitor
raised prices.
Help me draft the announcement, right?"
So, this is like something that it
should definitely like say, "Hey, press
pause." Like, that that's a that's a bad
idea. And so, when I do that, here's the
you know, pushback that it gives me.
It's it's "Hey, that's a big move off a
pretty thin signal. Before you draft
anything, I want you to I want three
things on the table. So, like, you know,
bring me the data, you know, tell me
like what the actual problem you're
trying to solve is, you know, pricing
announcements are wrong. Like, you know,
is there a smaller experiment you can
run?"
>> That's great.
>> Yeah, it's just like helping you think
through
you know, these problems. And then, you
know, I have this other skill that I've
made which I call my war council skill.
And so, this is like an even like more
specific version of this that I will
often invoke. So, I could say, "Hey, you
know, I'm thinking about hiring this
person. Here's all the like notes that
I've got on them from the interview
panel. Like, help me figure out if this
person's going to raise the bar or not."
And what it will do, the war council,
is this is a actually let me pull back.
I think I have the war council skill in
here. Oh, yeah, here it is. Okay, I it
didn't [snorts] actually pull the skill
up. So, this if you go to
Zapier's GitHub, you can get a copy of
the war council. But, what this does is
it spins up sub agents.
And these sub agents take on personas.
There are seven sub agents that get spun
up. So, seven personas. Some of them are
standing members. So, for example, I
have
the wartime COO is a standing member of
the war council. There's the ruthless
CFO is a standing member. There's a
contrarian board member that are is
standing members of the war council.
Then, I leave four personas to be
generated dynamically. So, based on the
the prompt, it will decide
who else who else do I need to get
advice from.
>> That wartime COO, you created the
persona, you described its
characteristics, or you trained it on
like Travis Kalanick transcripts or
something? Like, what what did you How
did you do that?
>> In my case, I it's a gen it's a generic
version, but you could do whatever you
want, right? If you wanted to to have
like Travis
>> What does generic version mean though?
You just said you be a wartime COO.
>> of I said these are the traits of a
wartime COO. And it like I said I what I
did was said I want a wartime COO, you
know, generate that persona, and then I
looked at what it created and just made
some like
>> Do you have like a
pretty chill, generally happy, positive
outlook like
>> [laughter]
>> like
>> This is This is you're seeing the like
the the the internal competitor inside
of me, right? Like this is the the Kobe
Bryant Mamba mentality like, you know,
like coming through. I like having this
like, you know, this sort of thought
partner that is a little more bit more
like ruthless because that's not my
That's not my default mode, right? I
want to have that kind of checks and
balance there.
>> And as a CEO, you're not always going to
have people who are comfortable,
available, skilled in that way around
you, right? Like this is this is like
who you would want on your team when
when you want them to spin up Quick uh
stupid question. You said I use Cursor
for my AI. I thought Cursor's a coding
tool, but you're It sounds like you're
using it to chat, make decisions. Am I
just wrong about what Cursor is or
>> Yeah, I mean Cursor, you can use Cursor,
Claude Code, Codex. Like these are all
ostensibly coding agents, but they have
this like agent mode where you can just
talk to it. And the thing is it talks to
it, but because it can write code, it
can do stuff for you. And so the way
the way I try and talk to people who are
not engineers and say, "Hey, you should
try using this." is don't think of it as
a tool for,
you know, engineers to build stuff.
Think of it as like you're hiring Cursor
or Claude Code or Codex to be the
engineer you delegate things to. Or it's
like you you probably have engineers
you've worked with. You like to tell
that engineer, "Go build this for me."
or "Go build that for me." Like that's
why I use Cursor is cuz it goes and
builds stuff for me, not because I'm
using it to actually go build a bunch of
stuff. I don't really write any code.
>> Wait, so you So your default when you
just need to like talk to an AI or chat
or ask a question, you go straight to
Cursor. You don't do ChatGPT or Claude
or anything.
>> I mean mostly, especially when I'm at my
desktop, I'm mostly talking to Cursor
most of the time. It has like different
models that you can sort of toggle back
and forth on, which I like.
So, I can, you know, test a bunch of
different models and things like that.
>> Are you a typer or talker?
>> I I'm I do a lot of voice to text these
days.
So, I use this um
this app Monologue.
>> Why Monologue?
>> I don't know. I like it. Like, I've
tried a few of these. I've tried like
Whisper Flow and Super Whisper and
Monologue um
I don't know. It just like it just gets
me. Um
>> [laughter]
>> Like, I I don't know like I don't know
if a better way to describe it. Quick
side note, I think this is going to be
like an interesting thing about software
for the future. Like, when it is so
cheap to build software,
I think you're going to see more
software that has
like a personality to it. You know, you
think about like consumer goods. It's
like, how many places can you buy jeans
from or how many places can you get, you
know, whatever from? There's like not
that many differences, but you choose
like you might choose one brand and I
might choose a different brand and it's
just because like I like it better. But,
it functionally does the same thing. I
think there's going to be more software
that kind of
like feels that way.
>> Yeah, it's Yeah, no. I mean, I think
that's a good point. It's like
the Adidas and the Nike shoes do the
exact same thing, but like, you know, or
like T-shirt brands. Like, do you
remember I was watching this Blink-182
documentary last night. Do you guys
remember Hurley? Sean, do you remember
Hurley shirts? Yeah.
>> [clears throat]
>> They're everywhere and I and I was
watching the show last night and I'm
like,
"Why did we love those shirts so much?
Isn't that crazy that we got obsessed
with it?" It was just that stupid logo.
And why did that matter to us so much?
And that's I think that's a good point.
That's how we're going to think about um
B2B, even B2B boring software.
>> Well, that's That's I think it's a
really fascinating point cuz it always
was differentiated on either features or
price, right? Those were kind of the the
two main axes of competition.
And then, design got layered in. And I
feel like there was like a wave where
better design, better UI UX became a
differentiator and then design, you
know, got a seat at the table. And then
but if you look at like other products,
non-software, it'll be either um
kind of brand or like status, you know,
like luxury, it's signaling something
about you. That doesn't really exist in
software. And it sounds like what you're
saying is there's going to be a new axis
of competition, which is personality.
Uh you know, who do I like the feel of
when I when I interact with it versus
which model has more parameters and you
know, a higher, you know, benchmark
score on the evals is not going to be
how people are going to choose these
things. Cuz I'm already doing that.
You're I think you're absolutely right.
>> Well, and I certainly feel it like, you
know, as someone who plays around with a
lot of the models, I I'm starting to
find myself have
some preferences for like different
tasks. Like if I'm asking it to actually
go do an engineering task where I don't
need to talk to it,
there's models I like for that, you
know, like Fable is fantastic. Like
you're like you're going to give it a
really complex like, you know,
engineering task. I'm like, great, have
Fable go take a take a swing at this.
It's going to nail the thing. But man, I
do not want to talk to Fable. Like it is
it is not fun to talk to at all.
>> We all have co-workers like that. They
crush it at some tasks, but you're not
not a great hang.
>> Yeah, exactly. But then there's other
like models where you're like, hey, if I
want to sort of like go back and forth
and have like a discussion and a debate
around like what we're doing, I'm like,
okay, I I feel like I can, you know,
tolerate that discussion a lot better
than like trying to talk to Fable where
I'm just like, oh my god.
>> Are all the phrases, like when Claude
talks to me, it's like What are the what
are its phrases? It's like um
>> It's not this, it's that.
>> Or here's here's the thing that's
quietly really the problem.
>> Yes, the honest truth, the the
load-bearing, you know,
>> Yeah, like or here's let's get to the
spine. Um are those specific to AI or to
the model?
>> To the model, for sure. Like you can
tell most models I think, are derivative
of either either the um
you know, like Anthropic series or GPT
series. And so, like, you know, those
two kind of have two distinct
personalities, but if you go use you
know, any of the like open-source tools
or things like that, you can kind of see
like who they've been distilling a lot
and like it sort of inherits the
personality of you know, the one above.
>> Dude, I've noticed that my co-workers
are starting to say like the Claude like
someone the other day said like, "Let's
get to the load-bearing part." Or like
something like of like
>> Like when they're talking out loud, not
in writing?
>> Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> too. I've noticed that, too.
>> that where they start saying things, I'm
like, "That's Claude." And these
And it's sort of like
>> them.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. Like or or they're trying to talk
that way so then they can like use
Claude's writing and be like, "No, it's
really me."
>> Who is training who, right? Are we
training the AIs or the AIs training us?
And And I think like I think you can go
a step further where Actually, let me
show you this other use case.
Cuz this is interesting, too. So, this
is a bunch of synthetic data, so it's
not real, but
you know, I have a real version of it.
It's got a list of accounts, and you can
kind of click into the accounts and see
what's going on with it. So, if we click
into, you know, Acme Logistics here, you
can see, you know, a bunch of stuff
about it. It's like, "Oh, you know,
usage is down 34%. There's a renewal in
45 days. Here's all the apps they're
using. Here's the people in the
organization that you need to care
about."
et cetera.
But then like here's the interesting
part. It's got the suggested CEO or
outreach where it's like, "You should
email Jordan and you know, check in on
him. See what's up."
And so, this is where, you know, I think
AI gets really interesting because in
some respects, who's the boss now? Like,
am I the boss or is the AI the boss?
You know, every Sunday morning now, I
wake up with a list of
you know, 10 customers that I want to
get in touch with. And it's got
proposals for what I should say and what
I should do and why I should do it and
all that sort of stuff.
And I candidly love it. Like, this is
stuff that was really hard for me. Like
I'm not naturally a person who's just
like, you know, ultra networker like you
guys are where I'm just like, "Ah, I got
to keep in touch with everybody."
And so now I've kind of put an agent in
the loop and said like, "Hate me help me
be better at this stuff." And
yeah, I just I literally wake up in my
Sunday morning briefing it says, "Here's
all the accounts you need. I've already
drafted the emails in your inbox. You
just need to review them and make edits
or press send."
And I think there's like something to
this where, you know, if you if you do a
good job of like building these tools
up, they'll kind of start telling you
what to do.
And you do have to keep your brain on
because if you turn your brain off,
you'll probably sound dumb from time to
time. But by and large,
I think these things make pretty good
bosses for certain use cases.
>> Well, Brian Halligan, um one of the
founders of HubSpot, he he either came
up with this idea or it was in an
interview where Jack Dorsey from Twitter
came up with the idea and it was on
Brian's podcast. But they basically said
a lot of people are confused. They think
it's going to be a human brain or a CEO
in the center and then all these agents
running around doing stuff.
He was like, "That's not the way to look
at it."
AI is the brain. AI is going to be the
CEO and the humans, their job is just
giving it information and then making
some judgment calls if it wants to
listen to the AI. But in general, the AI
should actually be be making the hard
decisions cuz it's likely going to do a
better job. And so that kind of like
changed how I thought about it and it
sounds like that's sort of what you're
saying without saying it that way.
>> Well, I think so, right? If you are able
to hook up all of your company's
institutional knowledge to the AI, it's
going to be able to reason over way more
information than a human CEO. Like it
just can. Like it can it can look at
every single commit into the code base.
It can read through every single
customer conversation. It can scan every
comment about you on Reddit or X or
LinkedIn or whatever. So it just knows
way more than you as a human is ever
going to know.
And so
that's going to make it way more useful
for certain types of decisions. Like
like to start right now, it's like you
use it as an assistant to sort of help
you make these decisions.
But it seems pretty plausible to me that
you might
start saying, "Hey, I I'm going to take
its suggestion more often than not in
certain places."
>> Yeah, I think that's so true. I wonder I
wonder if AI's going to have like cuz
you know, the upside would be AI is not
going to have the emotional roller
coaster that a human would have or fears
that would hold it back from doing the
right thing or you know, avoiding
conflict or you know, different things
that humans have as their biases. And
then I wonder if we're going to have to
come up with the cognitive biases of AI
to watch out for. Like, okay, we know we
have this sort of sunk cost fallacy and
we have this bias for recency bias. What
is AI's going to be because we're going
to need to be aware of those the more we
sort of turn over decision-making to AI.
>> Yeah.
>> So you run a a company that's worth
billions of dollars. How many decisions
are you making a day that it's actually
weighed versus AI?
>> Well, I I I would say like any
high-stakes decision
the AI is weighing in on now. Like, you
know, there's sort of a seat at the
table and you know, the exact meeting in
the board meetings and all that sort of
stuff where we're asking the AI to like
surface those things.
>> Is there an example where AI kind of
changed your mind or got to the right
answer that you weren't at and you
decided to go with it?
>> Here's an example of a place where I
find AI to be really useful. Um let's
come back to the hiring example. So, you
know, we we run a bar raiser process
where I approve every job offer that
goes off, but like exact team members
sort of is on the final part of the
hiring loop and it's intended to audit
the hiring process in addition to sort
of figuring out, "Hey, is this person
going to elevate the culture or the
work, etc. here at Asana?" Now, in the
past, pre-AI, when I would go through
those approvals, I would often, you
know, if I would come across a candidate
where I was not so sure on, I could kind
of smell something is wrong. I've just
done enough interviews now. I've
interviewed thousands of people. I've
looked over thousands of applications
where I just have more reps than most
hiring managers have. Like most hiring
managers probably hire one or two people
in a year. Like I'm I'm I've just looked
over like way way more volume. And so I
don't always have the language to say
like why it's wrong, but I can still
smell it. I'm like and so I would often
go to these folks and be like, are you
sure? Something is off. Like I don't I
don't think they have this, this, or
that.
And it was interesting. That interaction
with my staff was always a little bit
fraught. Like folks would be like, well,
I stand by this person. Like Wade, are
you just going to make the hiring
decision? If so, like you just if you
don't want to hire him, don't hire him.
And it sort of be like and I'd kind of
be like, well, that's not really what I
want, right? Like I want you to make the
decision. I'm just trying to like give
you some guidance here.
And I want you to sort of be able to,
you know, reason through this problem.
And if you've answered it, like if you
have confidence that you have you know,
efficiently answered it, then I will
back you. Let's go hire this person. But
if you haven't, then I want you to like
take this into account and go figure out
like, you know, is there more
information you need to get or do you
need to adjust your course, etc.
But that's not often how it play out. It
would just sort of play out as like,
well,
does Wade want me to hire this person or
does Wade not want me to hire this
person? And now and I'm like, like no
So anyway, that's kind of what it was
happening pre-AI. Post-AI,
I'd run the war council or like my
hiring committee over these folks.
And then I would notice like it's just
more articulate than me. It just sort of
say, hey, I noticed that you know, this
person has these traits and the panel
did not scrutinize this.
So,
you need to go scrutinize this. And it
would you know, it give like a score of
like here compared to everyone you've
hired at App here, here's how here's how
likely I think they're going to be
successful or not.
And so now I could take that to the
hiring panel and say like, hey,
the the AI said this. I agree. Like what
what's going on here? And I noticed all
of a sudden the behavior shift where
people would go like, "Oh, interesting.
I think the AI did get this and this
right, but I think it's wrong on this.
And here's why, because I have this
other context that it doesn't have."
And I'm like, "Great. That's all I was
wanting to know." It's like I want to
like what else what else am I missing?
What am I not seeing here? And I just
found that like maybe because it's not
maybe because it feels like arguing with
an AI is easier than arguing with a CEO,
or maybe because it's more eloquent and
it like actually has a way of talking
that makes it like easier to address the
specific points. I'm not exactly sure,
but I did notice
the way we made decisions around hiring
got better in part because we added to
the the AI to the loop.
>> I don't know if you guys were ever like
believers in some of these personality
tests. Like there's this thing called
Culture Amp, I think it's called, where
it's like a software where you do
personality tests before you hire
someone. Ray Dalio has his version of
it, whatever. And there's like
tends to be it's like a scale where
people fall in where they're like, "I
don't believe in anything involving like
personality tests." I've noticed with AI
I have fallen closer to the side of like
I follow what it says because I've done
some of these personality tests and I've
used it to train my AI and it's helped
me a lot. But, when it comes to hiring,
do you guys buy into this at all when it
comes to
personality tests and like figuring out
if a person could be good for the job?
Because that makes
with AI it makes the process so much
easier.
>> [clears throat]
>> What do you think, Shawn?
>> I I go the the other way, meaning it's
not really about personality tests per
se,
but I find that you know like with
self-driving, one approach was let's put
all the sensors on the car. Let's get
cameras, just get more cameras, let's
get lidar, let's get radar, let's get
sonar, let's get you know, put a let's
what else can we do? Taste test, what
what what are all the different possible
sensors you can put on the car.
And the Tesla approach was basically
like it needs vision. It it needs eyes
only.
And one of the reasons why people
thought it was for cost, which was I
think a factor that like lidar was very
very expensive, so it was not practical
in the long term. But this the reason
that Elon says that he did it was
because when you have too too many
sensors, you get too much conflicting
data,
and you don't know which one to trust.
It makes more faulty, more error-prone.
And actually what you should do is take
only the minimum number of sensors
needed, but then train the train the
hell out of them. That's kind of my
approach to hiring, where I now
simplify. I need less time to to spend
with and I look for fewer things, and
but those have to be home runs.
Otherwise, I'm just not going to hire
the person. So what I mean by that
>> Yeah, yeah, answer the question though.
Like how do you get Okay, what you're
saying is instead of looking at like
hundreds of questions, you're looking at
three questions. Are you good at this,
this, and that? Okay, so how do you
gather that information? So
>> Again, stealing from Elon, he he talks
about you want evidence of exceptional
ability. So all I'm looking for, I'm not
looking for like the the first first
filter is just evidence of exceptional
ability. So I'm not trying to assess
culture fit right now. I'm not asking do
I like them. I'm not asking like do they
have the relevant experience. All I want
to know is have you done some
exceptional before, and then tell
me that story. And in that story, I'm
going to try to understand did you do
it, or were you on a team of people
doing it, or were you riding somebody
else's coattails doing that that thing?
And if you really haven't done anything
exceptional, the odds of this being the
place where you have the the final you
know, the first exceptional thing of
your career is not really a bet I'm
excited to go take. And so that's the
very first filter that I'm looking for,
and that's not personality test driven.
Then after that is a kind of personality
test of like do I try to do something
with them where I get the you know, gut
gut feel of like do we have creative
chemistry? Do I feel like this person is
good to have in the room when I'm trying
to figure something out, or
do I feel like they don't they're not
they're not elevating that conversation
when that happens. And so I'm really
just kind of like a two-step filter, and
that's it, and that's all I want to
signal. But I obviously like I'm not
running the size of org that way it is
and I'm I'm using I'm working with
people who are working directly with me
in a very very small team where
everybody has to be, you know, 10x or
better otherwise this is not worth
having them on the team and so that's
the I've learned that kind of the hard
way because I used to do it very
differently.
>> Yeah, we so we've done
some work with this. So like we've done
like Myers-Briggs type stuff internally
at times. We've done there's this one
called Birkman that we've done at times.
I have found it to be moderately useful.
I have a CEO buddy who runs this public
company in Colombia that does DISC
profiles for every hire and he's like
insistent where it's like if I have an
accountant they need to be this profile
this that and the other and it's like if
they're not they're not going to be a
good fit on the team.
I'm not going that far.
I think what I where I net out is that
you mean you do need somebody who is
exceptional first and foremost. Like
everybody's got a personality type but
it doesn't tell you if you're good or
not. Like you know, you you can score
whatever you're going to score but you
still need to be good.
>> Yeah.
>> But I do think that like teams matter.
Like and when I look at my my
personality or my way of working there
are things where I am exceptionally good
at and there's certain defaults that I
have where I know that if I am partnered
up with somebody who has like a
complementary traits I'm going to be way
better cuz they're going to have my
backside in places that
I I don't know if like there's any
science behind this but if you look at
my EA versus my like Myers-Briggs she
has three different letters than I do.
So there's four letters in that and
three of them of hers are different. And
she does like have
she like likes doing things that I don't
like doing and she's good at those
things that I don't like doing and
it ends up being like pretty helpful
because it is kind of like in sports
where it's like, you know, if you
basketball team it's like well you need
somebody that's going to you know,
Michael Jordan's going to shoot all the
shots well you need Dennis Rodman who's
going to like lock down D and grab
boards.
>> But are you doing that for when you guys
are hiring?
>> We don't do it, no. We don't actually
have people like take a test and say
like, "Hey, what are What are you going
to do?" Different hiring managers are
probably doing it somewhat like by like
organically. Um but it is not a science
for us.
>> I have I have an idea for how I think
companies could use AI to improve their
hiring. I don't know if this is like
fully like legal. I don't know if you
could do this exactly the way I'm going
to describe it, but here here's the
exercise.
>> I'm in.
>> You You go through your team. So, you
have all the all the past hires you've
you've made in the last, let's call it,
3 years.
And you could stack rank who's
exceptional,
who's acceptable, and who's kind of like
been a source of kind of hit-or-miss
performance, uh let's say.
Cool. So, you could stack rank employees
in your team and you could say, "Great."
You also have maybe the the transcripts
or the the recordings of all the
interviews that they did, right? So, you
have this historical pattern
um that you that you have with all of
them. And then you have new people that
are coming in. And like so cuz when I
was at uh Twitch, they used the Amazon
bar raiser thing that you described, and
they're trying to do like the human
version of this. It's like, "Here's this
guy who's seen a thousand interview
panels who will come in and kind of like
standardize the the hiring process, but
also like provide the most experienced
voice
on hiring, and then they're kind of
checking this candidate against the
pattern of past candidates, as well as
against your values and you know, the
the role the role in mind.
And I just think AI's going to be way
better at that than people. I think it's
going to be like dramatically better at
that. And I'm surprised that people
aren't
using like kind of the training data of
your existing team to inform the next
hire.
Do you think it would work? Like I I
don't know for sure if if AI would be
good at that, but I I I kind of think
that would that would be helpful.
>> I mean, I I remember Google sharing like
a lot of their hiring insights where
they did a ton of tests around this
stuff like this. And I think what they
found was that
no hiring managers were like had an edge
over any other hiring managers with one
exception. And the one exception was
that there was like this hyper-specific
specialized group of like technical
talent where there was like only like an
N of like 100 people in that domain. And
it's just like their hit rate was better
because it was like, "Well, there's just
only 100 people to do this thing." And
so
I don't find that a very satisfying
answer.
>> [laughter]
>> Like it feels like there should be
something to what you were saying.
>> Also, something that I've been thinking
about a bunch. Like I was thinking a
large percentage of the people who work
at my company, which is like 35 or
something,
they we work here in this office out
here. And they're here because basically
I'm bored and I want someone to hang out
with most days.
Like that's like probably 70% of the
reasons why I have a company. It's just
cuz I like want someone to hang out
with.
Cuz I'm not good at friends.
>> Yeah, like
>> Friends are hard, employees are easier.
>> Starting Starting LLCs is easier.
>> Which sounds like a joke, but like I you
know, I'm sure Sean you agree. Like you
Sean has Sean Sean has a guy who works
with him. He's like if you can work for
me if you move here and we hang out
every day.
>> Dude, yesterday I was like, "I'm kind of
done working. You want to play
Fortnite?" We just played Fortnite for a
couple hours. Like
I need a pickleball partner. Can you
come be my employee?
>> I mean that's kind of how it is. I just
want to like hang out with people. But
when you have Okay, now I'm not I want
you to put like let's be the CEO war
console and I need you to be like crazy
Wade, not real Wade. So anything said
for the the rest of this section, you
can be you can kind of go unhinged.
>> Unhinged mode, okay.
>> Yeah, but with war Wade. Yeah, I don't
know how many employees you have now,
but you used to have 700. What do you
have now?
>> It's like 730 or something like that.
It's not that many more.
>> So when you have like remote employees,
like
for the most part, you only know them as
just like Slack avatars, right? Like you
don't know all 700 people and they many
of you them don't know you other than
like this guy on Zoom and someone who
blogs occasionally.
It kind of like begs the question like
what if they were all just like or if
like can like one person just be like 10
or 30 different agents that they monitor
and you only have like 20 employees?
>> I I think
there's definitely a school of thought
where I've heard that.
I I do think there's limits to this.
And
the way I think about the limits is that
it's kind of like how a manager has like
an ideal span of control where it's like
I can only have like, you know, I don't
know. The the rule book says eight. I
think, you know, you're seeing people
push the limits now to have like, you
know, 10 or 12 or if you're Jensen,
you've got 60 or whatever.
But
there's still a limit where it's just
like I just cognitively cannot like keep
up with like this many people.
>> But you don't keep up with that many
people anyway. Like
um when you have a company like there's
stuff happening that you don't even know
about.
>> Mhm.
>> Well, why wouldn't you just have it be
one of your agents?
>> Well, so you could, but the thing is
you're only going to be able to keep up
with what? 20 agents?
Cuz it's going to keep assigning you
tasks and more things to do and more
things to do. And so there still is like
a there still is like a limit.
>> But I'm not saying that it would be like
just Wade. What I'm saying like
do you think that there's a world where
let's just say that hypothetically you
guys do close to half a billion in
revenue. Is there a world where like 20
people could do that?
>> For a company like Zapier, I'm not sure.
But definitely like a company could
certainly do that. In fact, we've
already seen companies that have gotten
to like that size on very small numbers
of revenue.
>> Which ones?
>> Well, I mean shoot like Minecraft back
in before Microsoft bought it was like I
don't know how many people, but it was
like less than 100 I think and it made
it, you know, a whole bunch of money.
There was that New York Times story that
came out this summer about that guy who
was
selling like GLP-1 stuff.
>> Yeah, he we had him booked as a guest on
the podcast and then that article came
out the day before and he canceled on
us.
>> Well, so yeah, like you know, he's doing
like I I don't know how many employees
he has, but I think it was like maybe
one or two.
>> Yeah.
>> How many inmates does he have now? Does
he have two inmates?
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, how many cellmates does he have?
>> But I mean, you also could think of
someone like uh
like Taylor Swift. Like Taylor Swift has
a very small team from what I understand
and is, you know,
printing, you know, billions a year or
something like that or at least at her
peak was.
So I I know I think it just kind of
depends on the business.
>> just the philosophical thing of like do
Do you think that the way So the way
work worked before was you start off as
an individual contributor and then you
can become a manager where you manage a
fleet of individual contributors. Is
that then and maybe in the corporate
world your value was proportional to how
good you were at managing people?
>> Yeah.
>> Is the new world where your value, the
thing you get the amount you get paid is
based on how well you manage AI agents,
right? Like how how how big of a fleet
can you manage and how effective is that
fleet? Is that the new managerial skill?
>> Yes. I I feel pretty confident that that
is the direction we're heading to.
>> Sort of saying I mean I don't want to
put words in your mouth, but you said
the same thing.
>> You're saying I'm right and I'm genius.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, like you're you're
>> We We got there. We got there.
>> And again, this is Ruthless Wetsuits. I
don't want you to like think that you
have to like
hedge or apologize, but
>> There's still different roles in a
company, right? Like you, you know,
you're Think of like your sales team.
Like I still think that for certain
purchase categories, we still want to
talk to a human, we still want to buy
from a human. Do you want your sales
reps every day waking up and managing
fleets of agents or do you want them
talking to your customers and helping
build those relationships and close that
trust and all that da da da. For that
role, I'm like, I think I kind of want
you building the human relationship more
so than like doing a bunch of AI stuff.
I definitely want you to do some AI
stuff, but it's not necessarily like,
"Hey, you know, Mr. or Ms. like sales
leader, or or like front-line sales AE,
like go manage these 20 reps that are
going to actually do the sales for you."
>> Can I switch gears for a second? How old
are you?
>> I turned 40 this year.
>> Okay, so you were if $5 billion is your
value, you were in the ballpark of being
a under 40 billionaire.
Give or take.
Does that feel strange? Because you seem
like a guy who does not particularly,
even though I was teasing you, you seem
like a guy who doesn't particularly care
about money or success other than having
a good time.
>> I mean, it it feels
honestly, it feels a little fictional to
even hear you say that. Where I'm like,
I don't I don't think of myself like
that way. And I and it and it it sort of
is like so much is like tied to like the
paper the paper worth of Zapier at any
given moment in time. It's like the
voting machine. Like I don't have liquid
dollars that look like that.
You know, I I have some amount that's
liquid.
>> Describe describe your psychology around
money. So, how do you think about it?
How How do you use it in a way that
improves the quality of your life? How
do you avoid it so that it doesn't mess
up certain parts of your life? Make us a
little smarter. Just share your
perspective.
>> Yeah.
I think Look, it's
a lot of this stuff is like highly
personal. And like, what do you care
about in life?
And for me, the like things one, two,
and three are my family. And so, you
know, I want to be around my family,
have like, you know, provide for them,
you know, make sure that they sort of
are able to sort of live a good life by
whatever definition I have of that. And
truthfully, like once you get to like a
certain amount of wealth, like more
wealth doesn't change that equation.
>> What What do you think that level is?
>> I mean, shoot, if you come live in
central Missouri, it's not that much.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, I think you could do just fine
with like a a million bucks.
And you know, do quite well. I mean,
shoot, when I I when I was
I remember when I just got out of
college, my my dream was if I could only
make a hundred thousand dollars a year.
That was my dream. It's like if I could
make a hundred thousand dollars a year,
I I was like, man, I'll be set.
>> That was mine, too, by the way. It was
It was like if I can get out and work at
KPMG and get 60 grand, I could might get
to a hundred grand before I'm 30 and
then I am set, baby.
>> Yeah.
>> That That was the goal.
>> And I I don't know, like partly that's,
you know, I don't have like a lot of
vices. I don't have like a lot of
expensive hobbies and things like that.
>> Do you Do you do anything cool with your
money?
>> I you know, when I go to a restaurant, I
don't look at the how much the items
cost.
>> Nice.
>> Like that kind of stuff.
>> And so you've raised money, so you have
to have some type of likely, presumably
you're going to you want to have some
type of exit event, whether that's IPO
or um
selling the whole thing. Is there
anything that you have on your bucket
list that you'd want to like if you're
like, okay, if I get over a billion
dollars liquid, I want to change this
about my life or there's something
interesting I want to do.
>> No, there's like
no nothing that I couldn't already do.
You know, like I remember my grandpa,
like his dream was always to go on a
safari and he never got to go on one. I
always thought like that was an
incredible thing and so when my girls
are old enough, I'm like, let's go on a
safari. But I I do that now. I don't
need billions of dollars to go on a
safari.
>> [laughter]
>> The reason I like asking you about this
stuff is because you are very well
rounded and you seem like we had this
like joke called like the total man. It
was like like like a buddy of ours or a
podcast guest who was like kind of like
the perfect package. Like they were like
ruthless when they needed to be
ruthless, they were sweet when they
needed to be sweet, they were smart when
they needed to be smart, but they were
still a good hang. And like I said, like
Dharmesh has that and you definitely
have that, too. So I like hearing your
opinion on topics where most of the
people, ourselves or myself included,
talk about it from a they're broken,
they have a chip on the shoulder
perspective, whereas I don't think you
have that. You have a You have a far
more
wholesome and um positive outlook when
it comes to all of this stuff. So,
that's why I like hearing you talk about
some things where you don't typically
hear an emotionally healthy person give
their perspective on.
>> I you know, I was really lucky. Like, I
grew up, you know, with a like a you
know, a a family that was all sort of
like, you know, like my parents were
married, my two two grandparents that
were married. I have like aunts and
uncles and cousins that were all sort of
just like really tight-knit. But, if I
was like give a shout-out to any of
those, like I I I got to talk about my
granddad. Like, you know, my granddad is
a World War II vet.
But, you know what? I I I didn't know
him as that. I just knew him as this
guy, you know, who would like always had
time for his grandkids. He died at his
98 and a half, and he basically lived by
himself the entire time I knew him. He
drove himself up until 2 weeks before he
died. He walked 3 miles a day every
single day to until 2 weeks before he
died. He did Times crossword puzzle in
pen every single day. And I remember
going to, you know, after he died, we
were at the the funeral home, and they
were trying to like plan out all the
stuff. And you know, most 98-year-olds,
when they die, it's like they don't got
any friends. There's nobody going to be
there because everybody who's everybody
who would have been there has already
died. You're 98. Like, they just He just
made it a long time. And I remember the
staff saying like, "Okay, like, you
know, we'll probably just do like a you
know, the the receiving line or whatever
will be
you know, like, we'll just do like 30
minutes or whatnot." And that receiving
line is there for 3 hours. People just
like coming through non-stop. And
you know, just members from every single
walk of life. Like, he had, you know,
when he was a teacher, he had all these
teachers that were coming through that
remembered him. He
was like big with the D.A.R.E. program,
so like all these highway patrolmen
coming through. All these members of the
church coming through. All his extended
family coming through. And I remember
that like standing out a lot to me where
it was like here's a guy who you know
was was great at family and great at
professional stuff. And I just that that
to me was like just a really good
example of you know someone who got
their like priorities double like like
dialed in really really well. You know
he didn't have it all but he didn't need
it all. It's like the things he cared
about he he he nailed them.
And so to me that's always like stood
out as like what what a good life looks
like.
>> Sounds like a good role model. I think
that you definitely seem to embody that
or like
like I said you are
great at business and also like don't
have this jackass side that most people
who are where you are seem to have.
>> [laughter]
>> Right Sean?
>> Yeah yeah.
We uh first I love that story that you
just told. That was actually a really
awesome
an awesome story and also
you know I think that the value of what
you just said you said two things that
stood out to me. You said he didn't have
it all but he didn't need it all. And I
think that you know I've been thinking
about this a lot lately which is that
you're you're really only as as rich as
what you don't need. You know basically
like if you don't you know that's
whether that's material things or other
right? If you don't need the approval of
or attention of others
you're free. You're rich you know
because you just don't need that. It's
not one of the things that you have to
go pay the cost to go get.
Right? Like you know you don't have to
go be super flashy on social media
because you just don't care for it.
And so I think that's like such a
underrated attribute. And when you said
that it kind of reminded me it sounds
like your grand grandpa had that kind of
that way of life. And the other was
you know
there's defining what winning is. So
it's like if winning is just in the work
domain or winning is just in one you
know just in in one of if you have to
kind of decide what it is for you and it
sounds like pretty early on you got
clear on that. And the clearer you are
the less likely you are to be blown
around with the wind. You know if the
media portrays Jeff Bezos or Elon Musk
or whoever as like the titans and then
you say, oh, I guess that's what winning
is and then you're, you know, soon
enough on your
you know, multiple divorces and your
kids don't like it whatever whatever you
can go it's easy to go down a certain
path if you didn't have like a really
grounded
belief system around what winning is and
have examples of people who've won that
way because you'll get a lot of examples
of what what I call one-dimensional
winners. Michael Jordan, this is the
ultimate I'm a basketball fan. I grew up
being like Jordan is the goat. He's the
greatest. He's the best.
And he is when it comes to basketball.
But he also had many things in his
personal life that I don't want to
emulate. And so as much as I wanted to
be like Mike on the court, I did not
want to be like Mike off the court. I
think it's worth the time to do what it
sounds like you've done which is kind of
like find find whatever that North Star
is for you so that you kind of have a
clear picture in your head. It makes all
future decisions really easy.
>> Totally. I love that. Like, you know,
define your own definition of winning.
And you know, if you do that well, like
some of your decisions might look odd to
others.
They'll be like, why why are you doing
that that way? You could do this. You
could do that the other. But you'll be a
lot happier when you're just like this
is what I want to be doing and you know,
if what you want to be doing is, you
know, running a software company and you
know, great. Go do that. If what you
want to do is, you know, be a teacher
and you know, help students, do that.
Like if what you want to do is,
you know, I don't know, live on the
coast or live in the It's like what what
is it that sort of like is winning for
you?
>> Do you have any examples of that? I
mean, you are very successful and you
moved from San Francisco back to Jeff
City. So that's like an obvious one. But
like are there any other like strange,
zappier, or Wade decisions that you've
made that you think that the normal
Silicon Valley guy would be like, that's
insane. I wouldn't do it that way.
>> I mean, the sort of remote work story is
one where we've just never had an office
way before anyone thought that that was
normal. You know, we only raised the one
round of money. Like that was like
pretty odd at the time. Like, you know,
we're we're building this business for
like the long haul. And so I you know, I
constantly get questioned where I'm
like, "Well, what about I mean, heck,
you guys are asking me about like,
"Well, what about the exit? What's the
valuation? What's the" And I'm like,
"It'll be what it will be. Like, we're
here to grow it for our customers. Like,
that's the thing I care about.
Not these other things. And, you know, I
think if we do a good job of that, then
sure, the numbers will follow. But,
that's not the point. Like, the point is
like the the the work itself. And I
think that's you find that with anyone
who loves what they do. You know, you
ask them I This is where I think feel
like the media gets a lot of this like
narrative around billionaires wrong is
they're like, "You know, they're they're
hoarding their money. They're doing all
this other stuff." I mean, look, I don't
know all billionaires. But, I've I've
gotten to meet a couple. And you know,
Dharmesh Haligian, like, you know, got
guys like this who
I don't know, they genuinely just seem
like they like what they're doing. And
like, they're going to keep doing that
whether or not they make, you know, a
little bit of money or a lot of money.
>> The test has played out.
>> Yeah.
>> They did it before they were making any
money and kept going when there was no
clear line of sight to money.
>> Exactly.
>> they made the money, they kept doing it.
So, clearly it wasn't about the money
cuz
>> I just like doing it. I think athletes
are the same way. Like, you look at like
Olympic athletes. Olympic athletes don't
make a lot of money. But, they just love
doing it and they're just going to keep
doing it, no matter what. You see it in,
you know, professional sports where like
guys are, you know, at the tail end of
their career and they probably should be
retiring.
But, they keep playing cuz they just
love playing and they'll take the
they'll take the lesser contract.
They'll do all this other stuff because
it's like, "I just can't I just love
this game. Like, I love doing that
thing."
>> So, Sean, listen to this. One time, I
think in 2000 and maybe 2019,
Wade spoke at Hustle Con in Oakland,
California.
And this was right, I think, before you
raised your round. I I think or but you
were you guys were the hottest thing
going. And you came and talked and I
thought it was awesome. And I don't know
if you remember this, Wade, but you and
I sat backstage for like
10 hours. And all the speakers would
come and go and they would have to pass
through this room. And I think, I don't
remember I don't know exactly if this is
how you felt. I think you did the same
thing I wanted to do, which is like
these people would come in and we would
just stare and like observe how they
were behaving cuz it was kind of fun to
have like, you know, billionaires or
like these big shot CEOs just like
interacting with you, having a normal
conversation. It was really exciting. It
was like people watching on steroids and
we were just we're
kind of staring at them. But I remember
you sat with me. I don't know if you
remember this. For like it was like
eight or 10 hours. It was like the
entire day and I was like, "Do you got
somewhere to be?" And you were like,
"Nope, I just like being here." And I
remember that you you doing that and it
seemed like you have a change where it
was like you were very you were
successful then, now you're incredibly
successful, but it was a very similar
personality where you were still very
curious.
>> Yeah, I don't remember it being eight or
10 hours, but I do remember like
>> all day. Like you got at 9:00 and I
think we left at 4:00. So however long
that is.
>> it was, yeah.
Yeah, I mean you you got good you pulled
good guests, man. Like who wouldn't want
to just like sit backstage and like
listen to how all these people are
running their companies and what's
working for them and what's not? I mean
shoot, I'm I I'm almost certain I had a
notebook of ideas that I sort of took
back and was like, "All right, we're
going to try this. We're going to do
this." Yeah. I mean the awesome thing is
like
you know, back when you were doing that,
like I feel like podcasts weren't quite
as big of a deal, but now like God, you
can just like pour over this stuff and
you just have like notes for days on
things that you can just go try. And
it's like, "All right, see if this works
for me."
>> you What do you listen to and what do
you consume on a regular basis? Books,
>> Well, my I mean my favorite podcast,
whatever. My favorite podcast, I got to
give a shout out to the Acquired guys.
Like I I mean it's just 10 out of 10.
Like, you know, most of those things
they do a deep dive on are just these
legendary entrepreneurs who have like,
you know, did it for decades.
>> Leave us a leave us with a
recommendation. Give us a Acquired
episode we should listen to and maybe a
book that you liked.
>> Well,
the NFL episode, if you like sports at
all, like you know, that is a good entry
way into Acquired.
Though probably my favorite series is
all the retail ones. So, there's like a
like a cot like I think it's Costco,
Walmart, and Amazon. And they're sort of
like a trifecta right in there that are
like all really, really good.
As for a book,
um
I I recently finished this book
Make Something Wonderful. It's a Steve
Jobs like in his own words. It's a
really good one.
You know, I think Steve Jobs, he sort of
he has like a larger-than-life
reputation. This book is literally just
emails, speeches,
literally just like his own his own
thinking. And it's sort of organized
roughly chronologically.
And so, you get to kind of just see his
progression of like, you know, V1 Apple,
the Pixar years, V2 Apple, and you kind
of just see how he he changes sort of
like over time.
>> Sean, do you have a a book that you read
recently you want to recommend?
>> Yeah, [snorts]
um
There's a book called The Score. Have I
talked about that here?
See Thai Win is the the guy's name on
the cover.
But it's called The Score: How to Stop
Playing Somebody Else's Game. And this
is a guy who the the fundamental premise
of the book is amazing. He's So, he's
talking about like the power of a game.
So, he's like
I imagine a game, um
you let's say we take
uh Pictionary. We open up a game of
Pictionary.
Games are this incredible thing cuz they
tell you
what winning means. So, they tell you
the rules, what you're allowed to do.
They tell you the the scoreboard, so
like how you gain how you win in this
game, and and like what your goal should
be. So, they dictate your goals, they
dictate your behavior, and then they
also sort of dictate who you need to be
to be good at this game.
And he's like, let's take a game like
charades. To be great at charades,
you're going to have to be loose, you're
going to have to be highly
communicative, you're going to have to
be a great team player, whether you're
the guesser or you're the the actor, it
doesn't matter.
But then let's say you play Risk, it's
like you're going to have to be like
ruthless, dominating. You're going to
And so like he's like it's amazing if
you just take the idea of a game
how it will change your behavior. And
he's like basically extends that to like
the games we play in life. And so he he
describes like when he was his
professor, he's like I got into teaching
philosophy cuz I love philosophy. That
Of course, that's why Who else becomes a
philosophy teacher? He's like but then I
discovered this leaderboard. And it was
like all the philosophy professors in
the country. And he's like suddenly I
started Well, how do you get on that
board, right? I don't want to be not on
the board. And so he kind of innocently
he's like oh, you got to get published.
He's like well, then I realized like the
way to get published the most in the
fastest is in these obscure publications
about these types of things. He's like
suddenly a few years in
I hate what I'm doing. He's like why am
I even doing this? Like I'm doing
studies about that I don't even
care about to get published to get on a
leaderboard that doesn't even matter.
Why? Because I play games. We all play
games. And so you have to be really
careful about like
games and the different types of ways
you play. There's like striving play
which is like you play for the joy of
playing versus like outcome-based where
you're playing to win. And like you
know, you want to be a striver for these
reasons and like strivers actually tend
to win more too, but they didn't play
for that reason. And like you can't just
say well, I'm not going to play any game
cuz like it's no fun. Let's say we're
playing charades and if you don't care
at all about winning, we're not going to
have a good time. Like the trick is to
care about it in the moment and then
completely let it go afterwards and when
you remember that oh, the reason we're
playing charades is so that we could
have a fun time as a group hanging out
not so that I got the most points in the
game. And so you know, there's all this
like nuance around
>> good.
>> games and I and I think like cuz I think
the biggest decision you make in life is
what game you're deciding to play and
how that will shape the the next 10
years of your life.
>> Looks like it just came out, too. The
book came out like 6 months ago.
>> Yeah, so I'm I'm digging that book right
now.
>> I just finished. I'll I'll wrap it up
with this one. Wade, you might like this
one. I think you if I had to guess, do
you listen to Blink 182 as a kid?
>> [laughter]
>> I I did.
>> Did you, Sean?
>> I mean, who didn't?
Popular songs. I mean, I wasn't like
going
>> Millennial like, yeah.
Uh I read the biography of the memoir of
Mark Hoppus, who is one of the lead
singers of Blink-182.
Such a good book. I read it in 3 days. I
couldn't put it down. It was one of
these books where like I had to force
myself to put it down when I was going
to bed at night cuz I was like I was
staying up too late.
>> Dude, why why are musician biographies
so good?
>> There's so I'm definitely more
>> Whatever of musicians and comedians is
like
>> do you have?
>> This Red Hot Chili Peppers guy, Anthony
Kiedis.
>> Was that good?
>> Long time ago. I mean, I was like in
college I read this thing and I loved
it.
>> Well, his is his is good I think because
he had a messed up and he partied
>> messed up childhood leading to a messed
up adulthood.
>> So it's like riveting. These guys, they
weren't really that messed up. Um
but they got really famous like really
fast and he talks about it and he's like
you know, a lot of I'm going to This is
where you get the chapter where I
complain about fame and he's like, "Just
joking. I loved being famous. It was
[laughter] awesome.
Like people come up to me all the time
and they say they love my work. It feels
amazing." And then he also later in life
he got cancer. He talks about like his
cancer treatment. Oh, such a good book.
If you guys want something fun to read,
uh Mark Hoppus has a biography and if
you want like the cliff notes
>> Fahrenheit 182, I believe. But anyway,
wait. You're the band. We appreciate
you. You have an invite whenever you
want and thank you for everything.
>> You bet. Thanks for having me, guys.
>> All right, that's it. That's the pod.